<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A journey through statistics &#43;---&#43; by Giusi Moffa</title>
    <link>https://annlia.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A journey through statistics &#43;---&#43; by Giusi Moffa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;2017 Ann Lia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://annlia.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research interests</title>
      <link>https://annlia.github.io/jacademia/jresearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annlia.github.io/jacademia/jresearch/</guid>
      <description>At the heart of my research are probabilistic graphical models and their relation to causal inference, as well as their potential to aid translational medicine and health sciences. We aim to model and analyse complex biomedical data and routinely collected health data. Therefore we strive to develop novel statistical methodology specifically tailored to the research question and the nature of the data at hand.
Causal discovery is an inspiring technical challenge, where we try to learn about the causal mechanisms underlying a data generating process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visitor&#39;s guide</title>
      <link>https://annlia.github.io/about/jabout/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annlia.github.io/about/jabout/</guid>
      <description>Chronichles from a statistician’s journey
A drunkard’s walk in an attempt at building a Hugo website with RStudio and github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biostatistics Journal Club</title>
      <link>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2018/12/27/biostatistics-journal-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2018/12/27/biostatistics-journal-club/</guid>
      <description>Archive of the reading series from the joint biostatistics journal club of the CEB (Clinical epidemiology and biostatistics) and the Swiss TPH (Tropical and public health) institutes between spring 2017 and winter 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Series 3: Regulatory statistics</title>
      <link>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2017/11/24/series-3-regulatory-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2017/11/24/series-3-regulatory-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Figure from abovethelaw.com
  Date  Location  Topic      January 11th 2018  CEB  ICH E9 Addendum and Per-Protocol Analyses of Pragmatic Trials    February 8th 2018  Swiss TPH  Estimands and Their Role in Clinical Trials    March 8th 2018  CEB  A taxonomy of estimands for regulatory clinical trials with discontinuations    April 12th 2018  Swiss TPH  Estimands in clinical trials broadening the perspective (possibly with comments)    May 17th 2018  CEB  Multiple Endpoints in Clinical Trials: FDA Issues Draft Guidance (Parts I to III)    June 14th 2018  Swiss TPH  Multiple Endpoints in Clinical Trials: FDA Issues Draft Guidance (Parts IV to V)      Following up on the 2nd EFSPI Workshop on Regulatory Statistics, on October 5-6th 2017 in Basel</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk</title>
      <link>https://annlia.github.io/contact/jcontact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 21:59:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annlia.github.io/contact/jcontact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Series 4: To be defined</title>
      <link>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2017/11/09/series-4-to-be-defined/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 21:59:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2017/11/09/series-4-to-be-defined/</guid>
      <description>Potential Bayesian statistics reading list
 A primer on BAYESIAN STATISTICS in Health Economics and Outcomes Research Bryan Luce and Anthony O’Hagan
MEDTAP International, 2003
 Bayesian data analysis for newcomers
link to Springer
John K. Kruschke and Torrin M. Liddell
Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review, 2017
Quote from the abstract This article explains the foundational concepts of Bayesian data analysis using virtually no mathematical notation.
 The Bayesian New Statistics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Series 2 bis: Follow up to ASA statement - two years on (2017)</title>
      <link>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2017/11/02/series-2-bis-follow-up-to-asa-statement---two-years-on-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2017/11/02/series-2-bis-follow-up-to-asa-statement---two-years-on-2017/</guid>
      <description>Figure from Messerli (2012) Chocolate Consumption, Cognitive Function, and Nobel Laureates, New England Journal of Medicine.
Potential list of readings under additional p-value treatment
 Redefine statistical significance
71 Al. and Valen E. Johnson PsyArXiv Preprints, 2017
Appearing in nature human behaviour
with Correspondence by Valentin Amrhein and Sander Greenland in Remove, rather than redefine, statistical significance
and reponses by another large number of authors (Including D. Mayo) in
Justify Your Alpha: A Response to Redefine Statistical Significance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Series 2: To p or not to p, will we ever let it p</title>
      <link>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2017/09/07/series-2-to-p-or-not-to-p-will-we-ever-let-it-p/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2017/09/07/series-2-to-p-or-not-to-p-will-we-ever-let-it-p/</guid>
      <description>Figure from xkcd
The never ending saga of p-values
The ASA Statement on p-Values: Context, Process, and Purpose
with comments at
Supplemental Material to the ASA Statement on P-Values and Statistical Significance
was published in 2016 as an editorial in The American Statistician, with 21 comments from renowned statisticians, and a list of relevant references.
Meeting 1 - September 7th
The ASA Statement on p-Values: Context, Process, and Purpose (Ronald L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Series 1: Bad science</title>
      <link>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2017/06/01/series-1-bad-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annlia.github.io/archive/2017/06/01/series-1-bad-science/</guid>
      <description>For a light start in the field of evidence based science Goldacre’s Bad science is a good and enjoyable read.
Bad science wiki page
Order Bad science from amazon
Goldacre is a British physician, academic and Guardian columnist, very enjoyable to read, though provocative.
An interesting follow up is Goldacre’s Bad Pharma, more closely oriented to the world of drug development. Unsurprisingly it has attracted some criticism by reknown statisticians working in this field, such as Stephen Senn’s:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://annlia.github.io/jclub/statsteaclub2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://annlia.github.io/jclub/statsteaclub2020/</guid>
      <description>Causal inference according to Judea Pearl // Pandoc 2.9 adds attributes on both header and div. We remove the former (to // be compatible with the behavior of Pandoc :first-child&#34;); var i, h, a; for (i = 0; i 0) h.removeAttribute(a[0].name); } });  /*! jQuery v1.11.3 | (c) 2005, 2015 jQuery Foundation, Inc. | jquery.org/license */ !function(a,b){&#34;object&#34;==typeof module&amp;&amp;&#34;object&#34;==typeof module.exports?module.exports=a.document?b(a,!0):function(a){if(!a.document)throw new Error(&#34;jQuery requires a window with a document&#34;);return b(a)}:b(a)}(&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>